International Ladies Garment Workers Union. Stulberg, Louis, General Secretary-Treasurer. Correspondence, 1956-1966, 1959-1966 (bulk). 5780/003.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies Garment Workers Union. Louis Stulberg, General Secretary-Treasurer. Correspondence
1956-1966 [bulk 1959-1966].
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. General Secretary-Treasurer
5780/003.
14 cubic feet
28 linear ft.
Correspondence.
The Stulberg General Secretary-Treasurer records consist primarily of correspondence dealing with union managerial matters during Stulberg's term in office, though there is also some correspondence from his tenure as executive vice-president (April 1956-May 1959), as well as a small amount (ca. 1 linear foot) of personal correspondence in the collection.
3468207
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Center Staff
EAD encoding:
Casey S. Westerman, July 8, 2002
Biographical / Historical
Louis Stulberg was born in Poland in 1901 and emigrated with his parents to Canada in 1904. After graduating from the Harbord Collegiate Institute in Toronto in 1918, he moved to Chicago, where he worked as a cutter and joined ILGWU Local 81. Stulberg moved around the country, working as a cutter and union organizer in Toledo, Ohio, Chicago, and New York City. He finally settled in New York, working as an official and organizer in ILGWU Local 10. Later he held a number of executive positions in the ILGWU, including the vice-presidency, a seat on the General Executive Board, and the executive vice-presidency. He was elected president of the union in 1966, succeeding David Dubinsky, and served until his retirement in 1975. He died in 1977.
Scope and Contents
The Stulberg General Secretary-Treasurer records consist primarily of correspondence dealing with union managerial matters during Stulberg's term in office, though there is also some correspondence from his tenure as executive vice-president (April 1956-May 1959), as well as a small amount (ca. 1 linear foot) of personal correspondence in the collection.
Among the most significant topics are: civil rights (including materials on the 1963 March on Washington); collective bargaining agreements with other unions (custodial and clerical workers' unions); health care (including Medstore plan for prescription drug discounts to union health members); housing for garment workers in New York City; locals, regional departments, and joint boards of the ILGWU throughout the U.S., Canada, and Puerto Rico; relations with the AFL-CIO; retirement funds; union administrative matters; union conventions; union involvement in politics in New York City and New York State; and workers' compensation.
Significant individuals in the collection include Morris Bialis, Sol Chaikin, David Dubinsky, Herbert Lehman, Elias Lieberman, James Lipsig, Jennie Matyas, Norman Thomas, and Gus Tyler.
Notable organizations represented in the collection are the AFL-CIO Industrial Union Dept., the Liberal Party of New York, the ILGWU Union Health Center, and Unity House (the ILGWU resort).
Related Materials
5780. International Ladies Garment Workers Union.
5780/004. Louis Stulberg. President's records, 1945-1977 [bulk 1966-1975].
5780 OH. International Ladies Garment Workers Union. Oral Histories.
Arrangement
Series I. Subject files.
Boxes 1-27
Series II. Personal correspondence.
Box 28
Arrangement
Subject files are arranged alphabetically. Personal correspondence is arranged in reverse chronological order.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Civil rights -- United States; Clothing workers -- Medical care -- United States; Clothing workers -- Housing -- New York (State) -- New York; Collective bargaining -- Clerks -- New York (State) -- New York; Collective bargaining -- Clothing workers -- New York (State) -- New York; Collective bargaining -- Clothing workers -- United States; Collective labor agreements -- Janitors -- New York (State) -- New York; March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom, Washington, D.C., 1963.; Pension trusts -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- Canada; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- Puerto Rico; Labor union locals.; Workers' compensation--United States.; Correspondence; Organization files; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; Bialis, Morris.; Chaikin, Sol C.; Dubinsky, David, 1892-; Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1878-1963.; Lieberman, Elias, b. 1888.; Lipsig, James.; Matyas, Jennie, 1895-; Stulberg, Louis, 1901-1977.; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968.; Tyler, Gus.; AFL-CIO. Industrial Union Dept; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union--Officials and employees.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union -- Management; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Convention; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Union Health Center; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.--Political activity--New York (State).; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.--Political activity--New York (State)--New York.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Executive Vice-President; Liberal Party of New York State; Unity House
3468207
- I. Subject files.
  - AFL-CIO: 1957-64 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AFL-CIO, Secretary-Treasurers' Conferences: 1956-62. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Trade Union Council, Histadrut: 1956-58 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Anniversary, ILGWU 60th: 1960., Includes A.H. Raskin article in New Leader, "Sixty Years of the ILGWU." (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Anniversary," Film: 1957. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Applications (for Positions): 1949-57 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brotherhood-in-Action, Inc.: 1960-63 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Central Trades and Labor Council: 1956-61 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Congratulatory Messages (appointment as Executive Vice-President): April 1956. (Box 1, Folder 9a-9c)
  - Conventions, Union: 1959., Credentials Committee? (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Conventions: 1959, Delegate list and form letters (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Conventions: 1959., Hotels (agreements). (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Conventions: 1959., Correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Conventions: 1959., Newspaper clippings and printed matter. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Conventions: 1959, Speakers (correspondence). (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Conventions: 1956, Credentials Committee (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Conventions: 1956., Delegate list (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Conventions: 1956., Entertainment and exhibits? includes correspondence with Laszlo Halasz. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Conventions: 1956., Form Lars (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Conventions: 1956, correspondence and printed matter. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Conventions: 1956., Speakers (correspondence). (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Corset and Brassiere, Organizing Activities: 1949-51, Includes list of union and non-union firms. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Disability Benefits for Employees in Mental Institutions: 1957-59 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Dubinsky, David, Twenty-fifth Anniversary as President: 1957, Arrangements. (Box 2, Folder 13a-13b)
  - D.D. Anniversary; 1957., Acceptances (Box 3, Folder 1a-1b)
  - D.D. Anniversary: 1957, Declinations. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - D.D. Anniversary; 1957., Unity House weekend celebration (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - D.D. Anniversary: 1957., Printed matter (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - D.D., Dinner for receiving Freedom Award from the International Rescue Committee: Dec. 1966. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - D.D., The World of David Dubinsky Danish): 1958 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Fashion Institute of Technology (F.I.T.); Dec. 1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - F.I.T.: 1956-59. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Feinberg Memorial Fund: 1956, Establishment of the Israel Feinberg Memorial Studies at F.I.T. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "Garment Center" (movie): 1956., Includes script. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - General Executive Board Meetings: 1963., Includes minutes, reports to GEB, decisions and related correspondence (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - GEB: 1961-62. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - GEB: 1959-60. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - GEB: 1958. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - GEB: 1957. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - GEB: 1955-56. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - GEB: 1954. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - General Office (G.O.), Union: 1956-61., Office employee matters; correspondence (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - G.O.; Building Service Employees International Union, Local 32-J: 1957-59, Correspondence re collective bargaining agreements with Union. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - G.O., Office Employees International Union, Local 153: 1955-56., Correspondence re collective bargaining agreements with Union. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - G.O., Auditing Dept.: 1953-62. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - G.O., Death Benefits Dept.: 1959-64. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - G.O., Education Dept.: 1960-65., Includes correspondence with Gus Tyler and Mark Starr, releases, reports and minutes of meetings. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - G.O., Education Dept.: 1957-59. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - G.O., Education Dept.: 1954-56. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - G.O., Health and Welfare Dept.: 1955-64., Includes H. and W. Committee minutes, 1955. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - G.O., Investment Dept.: 1956-62. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - G.O., Justice: 1955-65. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - G.O., Jurisdiction Dept.: 1960-62. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - G.O., Legal Dept.: 1954-64. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - G.O., Mailing Dept.: 1955-60. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - G.O., Management-Engineering Dept.: 1956. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - G.O., Political Dept.: Sept. 1957-61., Includes correspondence with Evelyn Dubrow; Gus Tyler reports on campaign activities, releases and circulars (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - G.O., Political Dept.: 1956-Aug. 1957. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - G.O., Promotion Dept.: 1956-58. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - G.O., Research Dept.: 1963., Includes reports and releases. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - G.O., Research Dept.: 1956-62. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - G.O., Union Label Dept.: 1965, Includes correspondence, reports, releases, publications. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - G.O., Union Label Dept.: 1963-64. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - G.O., Union Label Dept.: 1960-62. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - G.O., Welfare Funds Control Dept.: 1959-61. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Housing and Redevelopment Board (NYC), Citizens Advisory Committee: 1957-61., Correspondence, minutes. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Industrial Union Dept., AFL-CIO: 1962-65., Reports. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Industrial Union Dept., AFL-CIO: 1959-1961, Reports. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Industrial Union Dept., AFL-CIO: 1957-58., Reports. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - ILGWU Cooperative Houses (Mutual Redevelopment Houses, Inc.): 1965-66., Minutes. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - ILGWU Cooperative Houses: 1958-64., Minutes. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - ILGWU Cooperative Houses: June 1961-62., Legal matters. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - ILGWU Cooperative Houses: Jan.- May 1961., Legal matters. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - ILGWU Cooperative Houses: 1957-60., Legal matters. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - ILGWU Cooperative Houses: 1957-66. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - ILGWU Cooperative Houses: 1961-62., Rental matters. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - ILGWU Cooperative Houses: 1958-60., Rental matters. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - ILGWU Cooperative Houses (East River Housing Corp.): 1955-62, Financial matters. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - ILGWU Cooperative Houses (East River Housing Corp.): 1955-62, Legal matters. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - ILGWU Cooperative Houses (East River Housing Corp.): 1957-63., Minutes. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Inquiries: 1963-66., Arranged in chronological order (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Inquiries: 1960-62. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Inquiries: 1960-62. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Invitations: 1963-66 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Boston Joint Board: June 1959-62, Includes correspondence with Philip Kramer; petition of Local 80 Pressers to merge into Local 12, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Boston Joint Board: 1956-Mar. 1959. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Chicago Joint Board: 1961-62, Includes correspondence with Morris Bialis. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Chicago Joint Board: 1959-60 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Chicago Joint Board: 1956-58. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Cloak Out-of-town Dept.: 1957-62., Includes correspondence with George Rubin. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Eastern Region: 1960-64., Includes correspondence with Israel Horowitz and Edward Kramer. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Eastern Region: 1956-59. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Eastern Region, Retirement Fund: 1956-63., Includes minutes of the Board of Trustees, Retirement Fund. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Harrisburg and Allentown (Central and Western Pennsylvania District): 1957-58. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Hawaii: Mar. 1959-61., Correspondence with Abraham Plotkin, special emphasis on industrial homework in the garment industry. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Hawaii: 1958-Feb. 1959. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Hawaii: 1958-59, Applications, employees (Hawaiian Casuals), employers' lists (Needle Trades Buyers Association). (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Hawaii: 1958-59., Homework Bill, correspondence re hearings and bills; Needle Trades Schools, correspondence and new rules. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Hawaii: 1958-59., Lists, negotiations and contract agreement with Shaheen Shop; shop lists; Union label. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Illinois: 1955-59, Includes correspondence with Midwestern and Southwestern Offices. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board: 1960-62., Correspondence with Isidor Stenzor. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board: 1959. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board: 1954-58 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Los Angeles Dress and Sportswear Joint Board: 1958-61, Correspondence with John Ulene and Union members. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Los Angeles Dress and Sportswear Joint Board: 1955-57. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Miami Joint Council: 1959-62. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Miami Joint Council: 1951-58., Correspondence, with Max Wexler (State Director) and Samuel Macy. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Montreal Dress Joint Board: 1962., Includes correspondence with Bernard Shane, reports of Canadian locals. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Montreal Dress Joint Board: July 1960-61. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Montreal Dress Joint Board: July 1959-June 1960., Includes correspondence from Montreal Joint Council. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Montreal Dress Joint Board: Aug. 1958-May 1959. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Montreal Dress Joint Board: Aug. 1957-July 1958. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Montreal Dress Joint Board: April 1956-July 1957. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - New York Cloak Joint Board: 1957-62., Includes correspondence with Henoch Mendelsund. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - N.Y. Dress Joint Board: 1961-62., Correspondence with Charles Zimmerman and Nathaniel Minkoff. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - N.Y. Dress Joint Board: 1956-60. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Northeast Dept.: 1963-65., Correspondence with David Gingold and Sol C. Chaikin. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Northeast Dept.: 1961-62. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Northeast Dept.: 1955-60. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Ohio-Kentucky Region: Nov. 1960-62., Includes correspondence with Nicholas Kirtzman, with emphasis on agreements with firms. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Ohio-Kentucky Region: Dec. 1959-Oct. 1960. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Ohio-Kentucky Region: June 1958-Nov. 1959. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Ohio-Kentucky Region: July 1956-May 1958. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Pacific Coast Region; 1960-62., Includes correspondence with Samuel Otto. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Pacific Coast Region: April 1956-59. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Philadelphia Dress Joint Board: 1960-62. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Philadelphia Dress Joint Board: 1956-59. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Pennsylvania: 1956-60., Locals. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Puerto Rico: 1961-62., Correspondence with Jerry Schoen and Robert Gladnick. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Puerto Rico: Sept. 1960-July 1961. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Puerto Rico: Jan-Aug. 1960. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Puerto Rico: 1959 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Puerto Rico: 1957-58. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Puerto Rico: 1955-56., Includes memo submitted by Frederick F. Umhey in behalf of the Union to the Special Industry Committee No. 15 for P.R., "Increased Minimum Wages for the Puerto Rican Needle Workers," Jan. 1954. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Puerto Rico: 1960-61, Correspondence arranged alphabetically by shop, A-G. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Puerto Rico: 1960-61. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Puerto Rico: 1957-59., Shops, A-D. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Puerto Rico: 1957-59., Shops, E-K. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Puerto Rico: 1957-59., Shops, L-P. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Puerto Rico: 1957-59., Shops, R-S. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Puerto Rico: 1957-59, Shops, T-Z. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Puerto Rico: 1956., Shops, A-N. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Puerto Rico: 1956., Shops, P-Z. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - San Francisco Joint Board: 1959-61., Correspondence with Jennie Matyas. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - San Francisco Joint Board: 1956-Aug. 1959. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Southeastern Region: 1961-62., Includes correspondence with E. T. Kehrer (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Southeastern Region: 1961. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Southeastern Region: 1960. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Southeastern Region: 1959 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Southeastern Region: Mar.-Dec. 1958. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Southeastern Region; Sept. 1957-Feb. 1958. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Southeastern Region: 1956-Aug. 1957. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Southeastern Region: April-Sept. 1957., Includes correspondence with Meyer Perlstein, resignation letter (June 1957). (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Southeastern Region: Oct. 1956-Mar. 1957. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Southeastern Region: 1955-Sept. 1956. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Lower Southwest Dept. 1958., Includes correspondence with Sol C. Chaikin. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Lower Southwest Dept.: 1957. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Lower Southwest Dept.: 1956. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Lower Southwest Dept., Bernhard Altmann Texas Corp.: 1956-58., Correspondence with Sol C. Chaikin re organizational drive and strike. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - South Jersey (Philadelphia) Joint Board: 1959-60, Correspondence with Morris Dobren. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - South Jersey (Philadelphia) Joint Board: 1957-58., Correspondence with Barnett Karp. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - St. Louis Dress Joint Board: 1960-62., Correspondence with Frederick Siems. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - St. Louis Dress Joint Board: 1957-59. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Toronto Joint Board: 1960-62., Correspondence with Samuel Kraisman. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Toronto Joint Board: 1959., Includes report on the Toronto Cloak and Suit Employees Retirement Fund. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Toronto Joint Board: 1956-58. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Twin Cities Joint Board: 1956-58., Includes correspondence with Michael Finkelstein. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Upper South Dept.: 1961-62., Includes correspondence with Angela Bambace. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Upper South Dept.: 1960. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Upper South Dept.: June 1956-59. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Vancouver, British Columbia: 1956. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Washington, Seattle: 1955-57., Correspondence bet. James Lipsig and Eloise Pratt, Local 184. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Winnipeg Joint Board: 1956-62., Includes correspondence with Sam Herbst (organizer). (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Jonathan Logan: 1949-55., Correspondence with Adolph Berle (Jr.) re agreement with firm, 1949. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Labor Day Parade: 1959-61. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Liberal Party: 1964-65. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Liberal Party: 1960-63. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Liberal Party: 1952-59. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Lieberman, Elias: 1955-57. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Loans and Endorsements: 1957-65. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Local 10, NYC: 1960-62., Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union. Includes correspondence with Moe Falikman and Local members. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Local 10: 1956-59. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Local 20, N.Y.C.: 1960-62., Waterproof Garment Workers Union. Correspondence with Local members with emphasis on complaints. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Local 20: 1956-59. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Local 22: N.Y.C.: 1954-62., Dressmakers. Includes correspondence with Charles Zimmerman and Israel Breslow. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Local 23, N.Y.C.: 1959-62., Skirt and Sportswear Workers. Correspondence with Shelley Appleton. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Local 23: 1956-59., Includes correspondence with Louis Reiss. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Local 25, N.Y.C.: 1960-62., Blouse and Waistmakers. Correspondence with Charles Kreindler. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Local 25: 1955-59. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Local 30, N.Y.C.: 1954-62., Designers Guild of Ladies Apparel. Correspondence with Benjamin Moser and Harry Tuvim. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Local 32, N.Y.C.: 1956-62., Corset and Brassiere Workers Union. Includes correspondence with Max Goldenberg and Abraham Snyder (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Local 35, N.Y.C.: 1957-58., Cloak, Skirt and Dress Pressers Union. Correspondence with Morris Kovler and Joseph Breslaw. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Local 38, N.Y.C.: 1956-60., Theatrical costume, Ladies' Tailors, Custom Dress and Alteration Workers Union. Correspondence with Luigi Quintiliano and Isidore Sorkin (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Local 40, N.Y.C.: 1956-62., Belt Makers Union. Correspondence with Henry Schwartz. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Local 48, N.Y.C.: 1954-60, Italian Cloak, Suit and Skirt Makers' Union. Correspondence with E. Howard Molisani; letter from Norman Thomas to James Lipsig re Maria Cascio case, Jan. 1960. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Local 60, 60-A, N.Y.C.: 1959-62., Dress and Waist Pressers Union (60), Dress Shipping Clerks Union (60-A). Correspondence with William Schwartz; correspondence re Jack Spitzer case and Local election, Feb. 1959. (Box 21, Folder 2a-2b)
  - Local 60, 60-A: 1956-58. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Local 62, N.Y.C.: 1959-62., Undergarment and Negligee Workers Union. Includes correspondence with Matthew Schoenwald. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Local 62: 1956-58. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Local 64, N.Y.C.: 1957, 1960., Buttonhole Makers Union (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Local 66, N.Y.C.: 1956-60., Bonnaz Embroideries, Trucking, Pleating and Allied Crafts Union. Includes correspondence with Murray Gross. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Local 89, N.Y.C.: 1960-62., Italian Dress fie Waistmakers Union. Includes correspondence with Luigi Antonini. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Local 89: 1955-59. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Local 91, N.Y.C.: 1961-62., Children's Dress, Infants Wear, Housedress and Bathrobe Makers Union. Correspondence with Harry Greenberg. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Local 91, N.Y.C.: 1955-60. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Local 98, N.Y.C.: 1956-60., Rubberized Novelty and Plastic Fabric Workers Union. Includes correspondence with Daniel Nisnavits re jurisdictional dispute with Local 142, 1958. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Local 99, N.Y.C.: 1956-60., Office and Distribution Employees Union. Includes correspondence with Douglas Levin and Shelley Appleton. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Local 102, N.Y.C.: 1956-60., Cloak and Dress Drivers and Helpers Union. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Local 105, N.Y.C.: 1961-62., Snow Suits, Ski Wear, Leggings, Infants and Novelty Sportswear Union. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Local 105: 1959-60. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Local 105: 1956-58. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Local 117, N.Y.C.: 1956-60., United Cloak, Suit, Infants and Children's Coat Operators and Sample Makers. Correspondence with Benjamin Kaplan. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Local 132, N.Y.C.: 1957-58., Plastic, Metal and Novelty Workers Union. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Local 142, N.Y.C.: 1957-62., Ladies Neckwear Workers Union. Includes correspondence with Joseph Tuvim. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Local 155, N.Y.C.: 1959-62., Knitgoods Workers Union. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Local 155: 1956-59. (Box 22, Folder 11)